Berryman Family
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Clifford and Kate Berryman Papers, 1829-1963, undated, Series 1:; (boxes 1-7, sols 11-12, OVs 14-15, 7.9 linear ft.)
  - Printed Material, 1856-1972, undated, 1.9:
    Printed material includes clippings about the Berrymans, a scrapbook of clippings illustrated by Clifford, clippings of cartoons, reproductions of artwork by Clifford and others (including Cruikshank, Duke, Sykes?, "Bill," Nelson, Packer, and Tyrrell), publications illustrated by Clifford, printed material concerning the Gridiron Club, announcements, programs, and brochures. See also OV 16 for oversized printed material.
    - Clippings, 1856-1907, undated, (7 folders) (Box 6, Reel 4771)
    - Clippings, 1908-1972, (6 folders) (Box 7, Reel 4772)
    - Scrapbook of clippings illustrated by C. Berryman, 1891-1895 (Box 12 (sol), Reel 4772)
    - Clippings of cartoons, 1899-1936, undated, (16 folders) (Box 6, Reel 4772)
    - Clippings of cartoons, 1937-1949, (20 folders) (Box 7, Reel 4772)
    - Reproductions of artwork by C. Berryman, undated (Box 7, Reel 4773)
    - Reproductions of artwork by others, undated, (4 folders) (Box 7, Reel 4773)
    - Publications illustrated by C. Berryman, poems, undated (Box 7, Reel 4773)
    - Publications illustrated by C. Berryman, American Statesman booklet, 1899 (Box 7, Reel 4773)
    - Publications illustrated by C. Berryman, book Berryman Cartoons, 1900 (Box 7, Reel 4773)
    - Publications illustrated by C. Berryman, Taft Truths magazine, 1912 (Box 7, Reel 4773)
    - Publications illustrated by C. Berryman, book The Cartoon Book, 1918 (Box 7, Reel 4773)
    - Publications illustrated by C. Berryman, National Press Club Yearbook, 1936 (Box 7, Reel 4773)
    - Publications illustrated by C. Berryman, book The Campaign Of '48 In Star Cartoons, 1948 (Box 7, Reel 4773)
    - Printed material concerning the Gridiron Club, 1912-1945 (Box 7, Reel 4773)
    - Announcements and programs, 1894-1946, undated, (3 folders) (Box 7, Reel 4773)
    - Brochures, 1908-1942, undated (Box 7, Reel 4773)
    - Miscellaneous printed material, 1860-1916 (Box 7, Reel 4773)
  - Photographs, 1892-1949, undated, 1.10:
    Photographs are of Clifford, Kate, various family members, and friends including William Jennings Bryan, Franklin D. Roosevelt, and William Howard Taft at a ballpark. There are also photographs of miscellaneous events, travel views (of Washington D.C., Mount Vernon and the Grand Canyon), and artwork. Miscellaneous politicians include speakers Clark, Cannon, and Gillette, a view of the House of Representatives (with C. Berryman to the left of the clock?) and James K. Vardaman, Mississippi Senator from 1914. Miscellaneous events show Clifford Berryman posing with various groups and individuals, including Marietta Andrews. See also box 12 (sol) for oversized photographs.
    - Clifford Berryman (see also sol 12), 1892-1949, (5 folders) (Box 7, Reel 4773)
    - Kate Berryman, 1895-1901 (Box 7, Reel 4773)
    - Family members, 1899-1903 (Box 7, Reel 4773)
    - Children of Berryman's friends, 1899-1911, undated (Box 7, Reel 4773)
    - Friends, miscellaneous, 1899-1911 (Box 7, Reel 4773)
    - Friends, William Jennings Bryan, 1915, (autographed mat) (Box 7, Reel 4773)
    - Friends, Charles D. Hilles, 1911, (autographed mat) (Box 7, Reel 4773)
    - Friends, L. C. Moore, undated, (hand-colored tintype) (Box 7, Reel 4773)
    - Friends, Franklin D. Roosevelt, undated, (autographed mat) (Box 7, Reel 4773)
    - Friends, William Howard Taft, circa 1913 (Box 7, Reel 4773)
    - Friends, William Jennings Bryan, Josephus Daniels, Robert N. Harper, and C. Berryman at ballpark, 1913 (Box 7, Reel 4773)
    - Friends, Miscellaneous politicians, 1914, undated (Box 7, Reel 4773)
    - Miscellaneous events, 1925-1948 (Box 7, Reel 4773)
    - Travel photographs, undated, (2 folders) (Box 7, Reel 4773)
    - Photographs of artwork, undated (Box 7, Reel 4773)
    - Miscellaneous photographs, undated (Box 7, Reel 4773)
- Florence Berryman Papers, 1902-1984, Series 2:; (boxes 8-10, sol 13, 2.3 linear ft.)
  2.1: Biographical Material, 1918, 1957
  2.2: Diaries, 1935-1938, 1966
  2.3: Correspondence, 1924-1984, undated
  2.4: Financial Material, 1922-1937
  2.5: Notes, 1910-1956
  2.6: Writings, 1932-1978, undated
  2.7: Subject File, 1922-1947
  2.8: Printed Material, 1922-1976, undated
  2.9: Artwork, 1931-1961, undated
  2.10: Photographs, 1902-1942, undated
  - Biographical Material, 1918, 1957, 2.1:
    This subseries contains a high school program and an award certificate.
    - Biographical material, 1918, 1957 (Box 8, Reel 4773)
  - Diaries, 1935, 1938, 1966, 2.2:
    The three diaries found here were written by Florence, including the latter, which describes travel in the Mediterranean.
    - Diaries, 1935, 1938, 1966, (2 folders) (Box 8, Reel 4773)
  - Correspondence, 1924-1984, undated, 2.3:
    Correspondence in this subseries primarily concerns the Washington D.C. art scene. Below is a list of notable correspondents:
    American Association to Promote Teaching of Speech to the Deaf: 18 Jun 1936
    Amini, Dr. Ali (Ambassador of Iran): 04 Jun 1956
    Atkyns, Lee: 08 Jan 1946, 16 Jun 1946, 16 Nov 1948
    Byrd, Harry Flood: 10 May 1950
    Finley, David E. (Director, National Gallery): 25 Oct 1945
    Hoover, Herbert: 30 Jan 1930 (printed invitation)
    Kane, Theodora: 13 Dec 1945, 03 Feb 1957
    Kellogg, Janet Reig: 19 Jan 1932
    Lahey, Richard: 20 May 56
    Mechlin, Leila: 03 August 1931, 04 Apr 1937, 11 Nov 1939, 24 Mar 1939, 23 Apr 1939, 08 Jun 1941, 11 Jul 1941, 23 Sep 1941, 13 Jun 1943 (letter from F. Berryman), 16 Jun 1943, 1947
    Pattee, Elsie Dodge (American Society of Miniature Painters): 14 Dec 1934
    Perlmutter, Jack: 06 Dec 1945, 25 Dec 1947
    Sipprell, Clara E.: 06 Dec 1938
    Taylor, Prentiss: undated, 30 Jun 1945, 30 May 1955
    Truman, Bess: 02 Oct 1952 (printed invitation)
    - Correspondence, 1924-1945, undated, (20 folders) (Box 8, Reel 4773)
    - Correspondence, 1946-1955, (28 folders) (Box 8, Reel 4774)
    - Correspondence, 1956-1984, (9 folders) (Box 9, Reel 4774)
  - Financial Material, 1922-1937, 2.4:
    This subseries consists of a record of compensation received for free-lance literary production.
    - Record of compensation, 1922-1937 (Box 9, Reel 4774)
  - Notes, 1910-1956, 2.5:
    This subseries includes notes on the hard-of-hearing, artists' biographies, notes on the history of the American Federation of Arts, and lists of works by Clifford Berryman.
    - Notes on the hard-of-hearing, 1936 (Box 9, Reel 4774)
    - Artist biographies, 1926-1956 (Box 9, Reel 4774)
    - Notes on history of the American Federation of Arts, 1910-1947 (Box 9, Reel 4774)
    - Notebook: American Federation of Arts traveling exhibitions publicity, 1933-1936 (Box 9, Reel 4774)
    - Notebook: Statement to corporations on the Cultural Development Fund, 1949-1951 (Box 9, Reel 4775)
    - Lists of works by C. Berryman, undated (Box 9, Reel 4775)
    - Miscellaneous notes, 1937-1948 (Box 9, Reel 4775)
  - Writings, 1932-1978, undated, 2.6:
    - Lectures, 1937-1948 (Box 9, Reel 4775)
    - Miscellaneous writings by F. Berryman, 1932-1978, undated, (3 folders) (Box 9, Reel 4775)
    - Typescript: “Prints: The Commonest Form of Art” by William Ivins, undated (Box 9, Reel 4775)
  - Subject File, 1922-1947, 2.7:
    - Stained glass and Joseph G. Reynolds, 1922-1947, (2 folders) (Box 9, Reel 4775)
  - Printed Material, 1922-1976, undated, 2.8:
    This subseries includes clippings about Florence, a scrapbook of clippings written by Florence, unbound clippings written by Florence, exhibition announcements and catalogs, and picture postcards of World's Fair murals and sculpture.
    - Clippings, 1937-1976 (Box 9, Reel 4775)
    - Scrapbook of articles written by F. Berryman, 1922-1931 (Box 13 (sol), Reel 4775)
    - Clippings written by F. Berryman, 1932-1955, (18 folders) (Box 9, Reel 4775)
    - Clippings written by F. Berryman, 1956-1962, (6 folders) (Box 10, Reel 4775)
    - Exhibition announcements and catalogs, 1941-1957, undated, (2 folders) (Box 10, Reel 4775)
    - Picture postcards of World's Fair murals and sculpture, 1940, (2 folders) (Box 10, Reel 4776)
    - Miscellaneous printed material, 1928-1953 (Box 10, Reel 4776)
  - Artwork, 1931-1961, undated, 2.9:
    Miscellaneous artwork includes a 1931 silhouette of Louise Browning; an undated etching of a name plate for Ernest Buttrick by Sara Eugenia Blake; and two undated name tags for Flossie by Jim Berryman. The scrapbook of artwork by members of the Society of Washington Artists includes work by the following: Olive Acheson, J? Oliver Asher, Martha Moffett Bache, C. Bea---m, Mimi Debois Bolton (1936), Samuel Bookatz, Kathleen Bruskin, Melvin Buckner, M. Comes, Mary Cover (photo of sculpture), James V. Cupoli, Deo, Eboli, Clare Feiriter, M.E. Foster (1961), Ruth Galoon, L. Gomersall, Himmel, R.B. Hobbs, Cornelia Hollander (1961 photograph of drawing), Hounanina, Lois M. Jones, 1938, M. Keshishian, Richard Lahey, Lewis, Leonard Maurer (1961), Alfred McAdams, G. Milligan (1959), Marguerite Munn?, Ruth Osgood, Rennie? (1957), T. Rostad (photo of drawing), Mary Etta Sharpe, R. Shute (1952), M. Snow?, Trietro?, Yanosky (1961).
    - Miscellaneous artwork (see also sol 13), 1937, undated (Box 10, Reel 4776)
    - Scrapbook of artwork by members of Society of Washington Artists, 1936-1961, (2 folders) (Box 13 (sol), Reel 4776)
  - Photographs, 1902-1942, undated, 2.10:
    Photographs in this subseries are of Florence, artists, and of the jury for the 46th Annual Exhibition in Chicago. Photographs of artists include a 1938 photograph of Stefan Hirsch, and undated photographs of Victoria Huston Huntley, Ward Lockowod, Oronzio Maldarelli, and Boardman Robinson. Photographs of the jury for the 46th Annual Exhibition, Chicago, picture Alfeo Faggi, Ernest Fiene, and Mangravite Peppino.
    - Photographs of F. Berryman, 1902-circa 1925 (Box 10, Reel 4776)
    - Photographs of artists, 1938, undated (Box 10, Reel 4776)
    - Photographs of Jury, Chicago, 1942 (Box 10, Reel 4776)
- Jim Berryman Papers, 1919-1964, undated, Series 3:; (box 10, sol 13, 1.1 linear ft.)
  Jim Berryman's papers include correspondence, artwork and printed material. Notable correspondents include Guy M. Gillette (Senator from Iowa), July 22, 1943; and John J. O'Connor (Congressman, New York), December 8, 1936. Artwork consists of cartoons of family members, political cartoons and miscellaneous artwork.
  - Correspondence, 1915-1952, undated, (3 folders) (Box 10, Reel 4776)
  - Artwork, 1927-1948, undated (Box 13 (sol), Reel 4776)
  - Printed material, clippings about Jim Berryman, 1934-1958 (Box 10, Reel 4776)
  - Printed material, clippings of cartoons, 1930-1964, undated, (28 folders) (Box 10, Reel 4776)